<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>/dev/null</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on /dev/null</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 06:31:02 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bruhtus.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Git Rebase Chained Branch</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/git-rebase-chained-branch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 06:31:02 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/git-rebase-chained-branch/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say we try to develop a feature B, but those feature need feature A which haven&amp;rsquo;t merged already. So, to prevent the diff changes getting larger, we create new branch to develop feature B. And then, in the middle of development of feature B, the branch that contains feature A got merged into main branch and all the commit from feature A got squashed into one commit. And when we try to rebase the feature B branch with main branch, we got a conflict from a commit which previously in feature A branch.</description></item><item><title>Use Arch Linux VM for Linux Kernel Testing</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/use-arch-linux-vm-for-linux-kernel-testing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 11:14:44 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/use-arch-linux-vm-for-linux-kernel-testing/</guid><description>A Brief Intro Have you wondered &amp;ldquo;how can we test a linux kernel without breaking our linux operating system installation?&amp;rdquo;. One of the method is using virtual machine (VM) and in this post we&amp;rsquo;ll use arch linux in virtual machine to try out different version of linux kernel.
There are 2 scenarios that we will discuss on this post:
Using arch linux VM with arch linux as host system. Using arch linux VM with different linux distro as host system.</description></item><item><title>Install Arch Linux on Virtual Machine</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/install-arch-linux-on-virtual-machine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 05:48:13 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/install-arch-linux-on-virtual-machine/</guid><description>A Brief Intro In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll install arch linux on virtual machine with QEMU and add a shared directory between host machine and virtual machine.
Before we start, make sure to install QEMU on your system. If your system using arch linux too, we can install qemu-base and tigervnc package. tigervnc package for viewing the virtual machine from QEMU. We will be using SeaBIOS, which is legacy BIOS implementation and the default BIOS on QEMU (at the time of writing this post).</description></item><item><title>Unintegrated Development Environment</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/unintegrated-development-environment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 12:20:19 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/unintegrated-development-environment/</guid><description>After watching video about acme in this article , which introduces the concept of Integrating Development Environment instead of Integrated Development Environment which usually abbreviated to IDE, i thought to myself &amp;ldquo;why not having a development environment without integration at all?&amp;rdquo;. This might sound crazy for some people, but this is my development environment at the time of writing this post.
Just to be clear, this approach might not be suitable for some software development, such as game development.</description></item><item><title>Reflecting on Intelligence</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/reflecting-on-intelligence/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 04:45:16 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/reflecting-on-intelligence/</guid><description>Over the years i&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking whether having a high intelligence is a blessing or a curse. Humans, who supposedly have the highest intelligence over other living creatures on earth, seems like having more stress than other living creatures.
With those high intelligence, human make a lot of innovation and one of them is electricity. One of the benefit of electricity is that electricity enable human doing activity at night, and that can cause some problems, one of them is lack of sleep.</description></item><item><title>Manage Dotfiles With Git Working Repository</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/manage-dotfiles-with-git/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 06:44:55 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/manage-dotfiles-with-git/</guid><description>A Brief Intro For those who read this article without knowing what dotfiles are, it&amp;rsquo;s basically a configuration files. The purpose of backing up dotfiles is so that we don&amp;rsquo;t need to reconfigure our tools on a new system.
There are a lot of ways to backup and manage dotfiles, and one of them is using git.
In this article we will explore how to backup and manage dotfiles using git, the full working git repository rather than the bare one which a lot of people using.</description></item><item><title>The Time Artificial Intelligence Take Over Humanity</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/the-time-artificial-intelligence-take-over-humanity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 11:29:55 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/the-time-artificial-intelligence-take-over-humanity/</guid><description>One evening i read an article about if bill gates could ask a time traveller, he&amp;rsquo;d want to know whether AI eventually doomed or helped humanity .
Those question is quite interesting, no one really know if artificial intelligence (AI) will helped or doomed humanity. So, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it.
Rather than explaining about the history of AI that only a few people cares, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about what make people scared about AI.</description></item><item><title>Postgresql Export Query Result From Remote to Local in CSV file</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/postgres-export-query-result-from-remote-to-local-csv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 04:22:04 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/postgres-export-query-result-from-remote-to-local-csv/</guid><description>A Brief Intro Have you ever thought of how to get postgresql query result from remote server to our local machine?
If so, this short post might be for you.
How? Before we start, please keep in mind that there are other methods to get postgresql query result from remote server to local machine, the method that i mentioned after this is the easier method for me.
Alright, let&amp;rsquo;s get to it!</description></item><item><title>Postgres Exist Clause</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/postgres-exist-clause/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 07:12:44 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/postgres-exist-clause/</guid><description>A Brief Intro Have you ever wondering, rather than show the data, can we show the true or false if the data exist or not?
If so, then this short post might be for you!
How? In this post we will take a look at exists postgresql function. Before we start, please keep in mind that exists use subquery, so there is a penalty of subquery here.
The exists will evaluate if the subquery return any rows.</description></item><item><title>Postgresql Count Data on Different Condition in The Same Query</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/postgres-count-data-on-different-condition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 07:07:47 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/postgres-count-data-on-different-condition/</guid><description>A Brief Intro Have you ever wondering how to count all the data and specific data with a certain condition on one query? If so, then this short post might be for you.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
How? Let&amp;rsquo;s say we organize an event and we store the participants data on our postgresql database.
Now we want to know all the participants that registered for the event and all the participants that actually attended the event.</description></item><item><title>Postgresql Get Current Database Size</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/postgres-get-current-database-size/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 07:07:04 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/postgres-get-current-database-size/</guid><description>A Brief Intro Have you ever wondering the size of our current postgresql database? If so, this short post might be for you.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
How? In postgresql, there&amp;rsquo;s a function called pg_database_size() which computes the total disk space used by the database with specified database name.
We can use pg_database_size() like this:
SELECTpg_database_size(&amp;#39;db-name&amp;#39;);The output of pg_database_size() is in bytes, so if we want to display the output in a human-readable format (kb, mb, and so on), we can use function pg_size_pretty() like this:</description></item><item><title>Systemd Reset Failed Status</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/systemd-reset-failed-status/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 03:01:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/systemd-reset-failed-status/</guid><description>A Brief Intro Have you ever experience a failed systemd service and already trying to restart using systemctl restart &amp;lt;some-service&amp;gt; but the failed status still there?
If so, this short post might be for you! Let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
Reset Failed Status Now, if our systemd service has a failed status, we can try using command:
systemctl reset-failed &amp;lt;some-service&amp;gt; to remove the failed status and reset it to recent status.
Please keep in mind that reset-failed is dependent on Restart option, so if you use option Restart=always, there&amp;rsquo;s a chance that the failed status still there because systemd still trying to restart our service which result in another failed status.</description></item><item><title>Postgresql Count Weekly With Bigint Data Type</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/postgres-count-weekly-with-bigint-data-type/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 10:58:13 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/postgres-count-weekly-with-bigint-data-type/</guid><description>A Brief Intro Let&amp;rsquo;s say we have a created_at column in our database with data type big integer that has a value with this equation:
EXTRACT(EPOCHFROMNOW())*1000 Don&amp;rsquo;t ask me why the value of created_at like that because i have no idea.
Now, the goals is to count every data per week.
How? How to do that? Because we use a unix timestamp which look like this 1687746597339, we need to convert those into timestamp using postgresql to_timestamp() function like this:</description></item><item><title>Postgresql Update Multiple Rows with One Query</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/postgres-update-multiple-rows-in-one-query/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 15:01:42 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/postgres-update-multiple-rows-in-one-query/</guid><description>A Brief Intro Have you ever wondering how to update multiple rows with one query? Let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to change value on table A where the name is anu on year 2019, 2020, and 2021.
Rather than doing 3 query with different WHERE statement, we can do that with one query. Without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s go straight to it!
FROM statement Postgresql has FROM clause in UPDATE statement which let us use columns on other table, it use the same syntax as FROM clause in SELECT statement.</description></item><item><title>Postgresql's USING Clause on DELETE Statement</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/postgres-delete-using/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 14:07:25 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/postgres-delete-using/</guid><description>A Brief Intro The USING clause on DELETE statement is basically let us join multiple table and delete only the data from those join.
If you ever use mysql DELETE JOIN with INNER JOIN, then postgresql USING is kind of similar to that except it can only delete from one table by default.
How? How to do that? Here&amp;rsquo;s an example:
Let&amp;rsquo;s say we have table A and table B which is referenced to table C by id.</description></item><item><title>Docker Compose Down Without Yaml File</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/docker-compose-down-without-yaml-file/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 09:59:40 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/docker-compose-down-without-yaml-file/</guid><description>A Brief Intro Have you ever feel that you have too much docker container from spin up a bunch of docker-compose.yaml file? And when you want to take down all those docker container from the docker-compose.yml, you already delete the file?
If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, then this post might be for you.
Before we start, we will be using docker compose version 2.16.0 in this post. If you are using the older version of docker compose, then this method might not work.</description></item><item><title>Simple Guide Flashing Mechanical Keyboard with QMK CLI</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/simple-guide-qmk-flashing-cli/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 05:07:03 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/simple-guide-qmk-flashing-cli/</guid><description>A Brief Intro So recently, around the time i wrote this post, i need to flash my mechanical keyboard. The harsh thing is that, the GUI QMK toolbox only available on windows and macOS, meanwhile i use linux.
So, i need to use the QMK CLI to flash my mechanical keyboard. This post is some kind of notes for my future self.
&amp;ldquo;Humans live by forgetting&amp;rdquo;, some people said. Without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s get started!</description></item><item><title>Remove Specific Line in Vim</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/remove-specific-line-in-vim/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 09:03:52 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/remove-specific-line-in-vim/</guid><description>A Brief Intro In this post, we will talk about how to remove specific line in vim. We will be using this javascript snippet code as an example:
const app = require(&amp;#39;./jest-example&amp;#39;); const math = require(&amp;#39;./math&amp;#39;); describe(&amp;#39;app operation&amp;#39;, () =&amp;gt; { const multiplyMock = jest.spyOn(math, &amp;#39;multiply&amp;#39;); multiplyMock.mockReturnValue(&amp;#39;itu&amp;#39;); test(&amp;#39;call math.add()&amp;#39;, () =&amp;gt; { const add = jest.spyOn(math, &amp;#39;add&amp;#39;); add.mockImplementation(() =&amp;gt; &amp;#39;anu&amp;#39;); console.log(app.doAdd(1, 2)); expect(app.doAdd(1, 2)).toBe(&amp;#39;anu&amp;#39;); add.mockRestore(); console.log(app.doAdd(1, 2)); expect(app.doAdd(1, 2)).toBe(3); }); test(&amp;#39;call math.</description></item><item><title>Clean Up Untracked File in Git Repo</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/clean-up-untracked-file-in-git-repo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 12:33:36 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/clean-up-untracked-file-in-git-repo/</guid><description>Have you ever feels like deleting all the untracked file or directory in git repository is such a pain?
If you do, then this post might be for you!
Ok, first thing first, there is a git command clean which help us delete the untracked file. We can even use it with interactive interface. To invoke the interactive interface, we can use this command:
git clean -i . What that command does is prompt us an interactive interface with all the untracked file in current directory.</description></item><item><title>Awk Print Row Instead of Column</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/awk-print-row-instead-of-column/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 08:53:01 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/awk-print-row-instead-of-column/</guid><description>Main Course Let&amp;rsquo;s say we have an output from xrandr --listactivemonitor like this:
Monitors: 2 0: +*eDP-1 1920/344x1080/194+1920+0 eDP-1 1: +HDMI-2 1920/480x1080/270+0+0 HDMI-2 Now, we want to display only the second row which is this line:
0: +*eDP-1 1920/344x1080/194+1920+0 eDP-1 We can do that using awk with this command:
xrandr --listactivemonitor | awk &amp;#39;NR==2&amp;#39; or using process substitution command, like this:
awk &amp;#39;NR==2&amp;#39; &amp;lt;(xrandr --listactivemonitor) If we also want to limit the row and the column, let&amp;rsquo;s say the second row and the third column which is result in this:</description></item><item><title>Shell Process Substitution as Temp File</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/shell-process-substitution-as-temp-file/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 09:28:09 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/shell-process-substitution-as-temp-file/</guid><description>A Brief Intro This is all started when i&amp;rsquo;m trying to make a shell alias using fzf and git add -p command. And i was surprised that the interactive selection from git add -p immediately terminated before i can even press any key. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started, shall we?
First Attempt My first attempt to make that shell alias was something like this:
alias gap=&amp;#39;git status -s | awk &amp;#34;{print \$2}&amp;#34; | fzf | xargs -r git add -p&amp;#39; Let me briefly explain one by one the command that i use in my shell alias:</description></item><item><title>Replacement For Info Command</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/replacement-for-info-command/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 06:38:52 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/replacement-for-info-command/</guid><description>A Brief Intro Sometime ago, someone posted a tweet about a replacement for rm -rf $HOME/directory that is mv $HOME/directory /dev/null. When i took a look of it, using the ls -l /dev/null command, i found something like this:
crw-rw-rw- 1 root root 1, 3 Jun 11 04:21 /dev/null Now, what is c in the crw below
crw-rw-rw- 1 root root 1, 3 Jun 11 04:21 /dev/null After going around on internet, i found an answer in stackexchange1.</description></item><item><title>Guide to Make Your Own Vim/Neovim Statusline</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/vim-statusline/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 08:31:29 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/vim-statusline/</guid><description>We don&amp;rsquo;t have to install vim plugin to get a statusline if we don&amp;rsquo;t want to.
Introduction Hi everyone! In this post I will talk about making your custom statusline in vim. There are a lot of plugins out there that makes vim statusline way better and works out of the box.
&amp;ldquo;Why would someone going through all the trouble while there&amp;rsquo;s a plugin for that?&amp;rdquo;, you might ask.</description></item><item><title>Access Google Colab Through SSH and SSHFS</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/ssh-google-colab/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 09:32:28 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/ssh-google-colab/</guid><description>Have you ever want a terminal emulator in google colab instead of jupyter notebook? Well, here it is bois!
Skip-able Part First thing first, i prefer to use vim/neovim instead of jupyter notebook and that&amp;rsquo;s why i prefer to use terminal or terminal emulator to do things as much as possible. I know jupyter notebook has it&amp;rsquo;s own vim emulation, but it&amp;rsquo;s not as good as the OG vim/neovim.</description></item><item><title>Pyv: Minimalist Python Venv Management Tool</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/pyv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 11:43:18 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/pyv/</guid><description>This is a continuation from my previous post (you can check it here ). Long story short, this is a minimalist way to manage your python virtual environment. All you need is python and git.
What Is Pyv? Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief intro to what is pyv:
Pyv is a simple shell function that let you manage python virtual environment that decoupled from project directory.
To put it simply, pyv move the virtual environment to $PYV_dir which by default is $HOME/.</description></item><item><title>Split Up Vimrc</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/split-up-vimrc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 05:37:41 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/split-up-vimrc/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re the type of person who like to place all your source code in one file, then this article is not for you. But, if you&amp;rsquo;re the type of person who like to split up your source code into a few sub-modules, then this article is for you.
Skip-able Part When i look at my vimrc (vimrc is a vim config file for those who don&amp;rsquo;t know), i always feel confused where should i add new configuration for new plugin.</description></item><item><title>Managing Python Virtual Environment</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/python-venv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 05:36:43 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/python-venv/</guid><description>Have you ever want python virtual environment that decoupled from the project directory like conda but not actually conda (dejavu)? That&amp;rsquo;s what this post is about, a simple way to manage a python virtual environment similar to how conda manage virtual environment without python version management.
A Brief Intro to Python Virtual Environment To makes thing simpler, python virtual environment is a self-contained directory tree that contains a python installation for a particular version of python plus a number of additional packages.</description></item><item><title>Arch Linux Installation Guide (Feb 2021)</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/arch-installation-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 07:14:39 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/arch-installation-guide/</guid><description>Don&amp;rsquo;t install arch linux, install TempleOS instead. All hail HolyC! (R.I.P Terry). Jokes aside, please keep in mind that this guide might become obsolete because the nature of rolling release so you should always check the arch wiki installation guide .
A Brief Intro I&amp;rsquo;m trying to install an OS as minimal as possible but not from scratch like Linux From Scratch or compiling everything like Gentoo . I might try to install both of them but i don&amp;rsquo;t think i&amp;rsquo;m gonna use one of them as my main OS.</description></item><item><title>Linux Ownership and Permissions</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/linux-ownership-permissions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 13:56:01 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/linux-ownership-permissions/</guid><description>How to change ownership and permission on linux (and probably other unix-like system? i&amp;rsquo;m not sure). Plain boring and important.
A Brief Intro File/directory ownership is basically who owns the file/directory, for example, if we create a file/directory as admin or root in this case and if we want to edit those file/directory as user then we need to change the file/directory ownership because that file/directory owned by the root and we have no access to change that file/directory.</description></item><item><title>Git Repository Backup</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/git-repo-backup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 03:43:38 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/git-repo-backup/</guid><description>Have you ever thought that some day your git remote repository service account got banned or even their server went down? It always crossed my mind and if that happen i would lose all my source code. So in this post i&amp;rsquo;m gonna explain how to backup your git repository locally and to other git remote repository services.
Skip-able Part Git is a version control system for tracking any changes in any set of files.</description></item><item><title>Python Script vs. Shell Script: Command Line Use Case</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/python-vs-shell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 06:00:07 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/python-vs-shell/</guid><description>In this post i&amp;rsquo;m comparing performance python script and shell script that i&amp;rsquo;ve made. The script objective is to check git status on every git repo directory.
Skip-able Part Just a background story why i made this post
Have you wondered what performance between python script and shell script (or some people might say bash script) to run command on terminal? no? same, just kidding. I&amp;rsquo;m curious about shell script because i can do command line stuff with python script too which for my past self is easier to read.</description></item><item><title>The Difference Between GNU/Linux and Mac OS</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/mac-os-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 13:26:08 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/mac-os-linux/</guid><description>To make things clear that GNU/Linux and Mac OS is different and don&amp;rsquo;t expect both of them do the same thing.
Skip-able Part What motivates me to make this post is a tweet from someone named David Bombal that trying to install ubuntu on macbook with M1 chip, here is the tweet .
That tweet makes me wonder why would someone install ubuntu on mac, isn&amp;rsquo;t mac os and linux similar?</description></item><item><title>Manjaro i3 Edition</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/manjaro-i3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/manjaro-i3/</guid><description>A minimalist approach to new arch linux user or new linux user in general. No more, maybe less.
Skip-able Part Just a background story why i use manjaro i3 edition.
Have you ever bored with your current desktop environment? because that&amp;rsquo;s what made me wanted to try manjaro i3 edition. Why manjaro i3 edition and not something else like regolith linux? Here&amp;rsquo;s the reason: I want a rolling release distro because it&amp;rsquo;s kind of a pain to reinstall the whole system just to upgrade to the new version in fixed-point release distro just like regolith linux (because it&amp;rsquo;s based on ubuntu).</description></item><item><title>Zsh Aliases: Be Lazy!</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/zsh-aliases/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 09:40:36 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/zsh-aliases/</guid><description>Have you ever thought that typing a long command is such a pain? well, here&amp;rsquo;s one of the solution for you.
Skip-able Part Just a background story why i write this in the first place.
At some random time back then i thought &amp;ldquo;can i increase my speed while using the command line interface?&amp;rdquo; and there&amp;rsquo;s two option i could think of back then, the first one is to increase my typing speed and the second one is to make everything i type shorter.</description></item><item><title>Backup: The Options</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/manjaro-backup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 05:21:31 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/manjaro-backup/</guid><description>A few options about backing up your system, especially on arch-based distro. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly for linux, i&amp;rsquo;m not sure if you can use it for mac os or windows too.
Why Should You Backup Your System? In case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering why you should backup your system (for some reason), let me briefly explain. There&amp;rsquo;s always a risk of failure when you&amp;rsquo;re updating or installing a new package (to make things easier to understand, it&amp;rsquo;s basically a program), when that happens, do you want to restore your system before the error occur or you want to re-install the whole system from scratch?</description></item><item><title>Instasaver: Save Your Chosen Instagram Posts</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/instasaver/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/instasaver/</guid><description>A brief explanation about instasaver, a tool to save instagram post build with instaloader python module and streamlit.
Background Story Nothing fancy, you should probably skip this.
To make things short, basically i was inspired by Kevin Hazy&amp;rsquo;s project here . After i see Kevin&amp;rsquo;s project, i was like &amp;ldquo;can i make almost the same thing with python?&amp;rdquo; and that was the trigger.
If you ask me why i want a tool (kind of) to save instagram post, that&amp;rsquo;s because i have a hard time to save video memes on instagram and i don&amp;rsquo;t really want to use a screen recorder (said the guy who made something that took longer than learning how to use screen recorder and edit the result 👀).</description></item><item><title>Tiling Window Manager For Efficiency</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/tiling-window-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/tiling-window-manager/</guid><description>A brief explanation about tiling window manager and configuration tiling window manager that i&amp;rsquo;ve tried.
A Brief Explanation About Window Manager A window manager is a system software that controls the placement and appearance of windows within a windowing system in a graphical user interface (GUI). It can be part of desktop enviroment (DE) or be used standalone1.
So basically window manager is how to place a window.</description></item><item><title>Pavement Distress Detector Using Single Shot Detector (SSD)</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/pavement-distress-detector/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/posts/pavement-distress-detector/</guid><description>This was my graduation project, in this article i&amp;rsquo;m gonna explain what i did in my graduation project. This project was based on Congcong Li&amp;rsquo;s Project .
Diagram Process of This Project A Brief Explanation About Single Shot Detector (SSD) Single shot detector is a deep learning method presented by Wei Liu, Dragomir Anguelov, Dumitru Erhan, Christian Szegedy, Scott Reed4, Cheng-Yang Fu, Alexander C. Berg in their research paper SSD: Single Shot Multibox Detector .</description></item><item><title>About Robertus Chris</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/about/</guid><description>I am the sum of everything that went before me, of all i have been seen done, of everything done to me.
I like doing some experiment, trying things out, and analyze the results. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in shell scripting, tinkering with software (such as vim), eink device, mechanical keyboard, and photography.
I&amp;rsquo;m not the type of person who can do something if I try, I&amp;rsquo;m the type of person who tries until I can do something.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://bruhtus.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bruhtus.github.io/projects/</guid><description>Vim-como Copy or move one line in vim without hassle.
Repo Vim-groot Toggle between git root and file directory as current working directory in vim.
Repo Pyv Minimalist python venv management tool.
Repo Post Vim-peek Vim plugin to take a peek of the content at a given line number.</description></item></channel></rss>